Neha Nautiyal

Email: nehahaha@gmail.com | Phone: 732-991-2517 | Philadelphia, PA 19119

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/neha-nautiyal-09819880 | Github: github.com/NehaNautiyal | Website: nehanautiyal.github.io

SUMMARY

Full-Stack web developer with certification from UPenn expected July 2019, passionate about learning new technologies. Enjoys tackling challenges with strong organization and collaborative skills. Effective communicator experienced in analyzing and solving problems logically. Brings experience with HTML/CSS, Javascript, jQuery, and more along with a love of learning developed through 8 years as a chemistry instructor. Eager to apply a varied skill set to make an impact within an organization.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Git, Bootstrap, Bash, HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, AJAX, APIs, Firebase, Node.js, SQL, Express.js, Handlebars, React.js, Agile Methodologies, Heroku

PROJECTS

Lost in Textlation | github.com/NehaNautiyal/Lost-in-Textlation | nehanautiyal.github.io/Lost-in-Textlation | Project Manager, Back end Developer

- Managed a team of 4 using Git, Slack, and kanban style to create an app with JavaScript & jQuery that analyzes
 user-inputted text, sending it to AYLIEN API for sentiment analysis & Merriam-Webster API for synonyms & antonyms.
- Optimized user experience using HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap with a common theme throughout.
- Allow multiple users to benefit from using the app with persistence from Google's Firebase Database.

Rock, Paper, Scissors - Multiplayer Game | github.com/NehaNautiyal/RPS-Multiplayer | nehanautiyal.github.io/RPS-Multiplayer

Full-Stack Developer

- Created an opportunity for two users from anywhere to play a game of rock, paper, scissors with Javascript & jQuery.
- Optimized user experience using HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap.
- Designed a method to keep track of wins, losses, and ties for the duration of the game.
- Enabled a chat function that persists data with Firebase.

Trivia Game | github.com/NehaNautiyal/TriviaGame | nehanautiyal.github.io/TriviaGame/

Front-end Developer

- Constructed an app for users to test their skills on chemistry formulas of household substances using Javascript & jQuery.
- Optimized user experience using HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap.
- Provided user with 30 seconds to answer each question before automatically displaying the next question with setTimeout and setInterval.
- Designed a method to keep track of questions answered both correctly and incorrectly for the duration of the game.

EXPERIENCE

Upper School Science Teacher – Abington Friends School – Jenkintown, PA

Aug 2016 - Present

- Design chemistry curriculum for three courses (regular, honors, and AP chemistry).
- Build materials for class lessons to teach high school students.
- Apply strong communication and interpersonal skills to work with students as well as colleagues.
- Act as a technology innovator using new devices in the classroom showing strong desire to learn.
- Seek feedback to improve showing openness to critique and desire to continually learn.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

<u>Science Department Coordinator</u> – *Olney Charter High School* – Philadelphia, PA

Aug 2015 - June 2016

<u>High School Chemistry Teacher</u> – *Olney Charter High School* – Philadelphia, PA

Aug 2011 - June 2016

EDUCATION

University of Pennsylvania, Philadephia, PA – Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp Certification, expected July 2019 University of Pennsylvania, Philadephia, PA – Masters in Secondary Education specializing in science, May 2011 University of Pennsylvania, Philadephia, PA – 1 year of doctorate in Chemistry before leaving program

Rutgers University, New Brunswick, NJ – Bachelor of Arts in Chemistry, double minor in Physics & French	